<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freedom on Robert Marshall</title>
    <link>https://robertmarshall.xyz/tags/freedom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freedom on Robert Marshall</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://robertmarshall.xyz/tags/freedom/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When Quiet Becomes a Fault</title>
      <link>https://robertmarshall.xyz/writings/when-quiet-becomes-a-fault/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://robertmarshall.xyz/writings/when-quiet-becomes-a-fault/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When Quiet Becomes a Fault&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have often noticed, with a quiet but persistent discomfort, how easy it is to disappear into myself without even realising it. Not physically, of course, but psychologically, emotionally, morally. There is a subtle, almost imperceptible erosion that occurs when I keep my unhappiness unspoken, when I convince myself that silence is a virtue. Each day I swallow what I feel, push down irritation, tuck disappointment behind polite smiles. The cost is invisible at first. My actions appear orderly, my life functional. But inside, a slow corrosion begins, eating away at the contours of who I am. The self I believe intact begins to fray. I notice, too late, that endurance without articulation is not strength but dissolution. What is left is a reflection of what I imagine others expect me to be, a shadow of the person I know I am. This shadow moves through the day, interacting with the world as though it were sufficient, while the real self grows muted, shrinking under its own containment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine and the Soul</title>
      <link>https://robertmarshall.xyz/writings/machine-and-the-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://robertmarshall.xyz/writings/machine-and-the-soul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Machine and the Soul&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern man has inherited a world that promises convenience and delivers compliance. We are told we are freer than ever, yet everywhere we find ourselves managed—by bureaucracies, algorithms, psychological assessments, and false choices preordained by systems that presume to know us better than we know ourselves. This is not freedom. It is domestication.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The machine—the vast network of institutions, ideologies, and devices that govern modern life—does not threaten us in the old ways. It no longer needs to ban books or jail dissidents. It simply distracts us, flatters us, diagnoses us, and nudges us until we mistake obedience for choice and sedation for peace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
