<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Greek Literature on Robert Marshall</title>
    <link>https://robertmarshall.xyz/tags/greek-literature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Greek Literature on Robert Marshall</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://robertmarshall.xyz/tags/greek-literature/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wrath of Achilles</title>
      <link>https://robertmarshall.xyz/writings/wrath-of-achilles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://robertmarshall.xyz/writings/wrath-of-achilles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrath of Achilles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first line strikes like a war trumpet: &lt;em&gt;“Sing, goddess, the anger of Achilles son of Peleus, that brought countless ills upon the Achaeans.”&lt;/em&gt; I remember rereading it aloud one evening, the ancient words pressing themselves onto my tongue like incantations. This anger—&lt;em&gt;mēnin&lt;/em&gt;—is no petty grievance but something elemental, corrosive, and divine. From the outset, Homer does not present war as glorious or redemptive, but as a theatre of rage and loss, governed by capricious gods and fragile men.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Man of Many Turns</title>
      <link>https://robertmarshall.xyz/writings/a-man-of-many-turns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://robertmarshall.xyz/writings/a-man-of-many-turns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Man of Many Turns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have always preferred &lt;em&gt;nostos&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;kleos&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;Iliad&lt;/em&gt; dazzles, yes, but the &lt;em&gt;Odyssey&lt;/em&gt; lingers. It is quieter, more cunning, and in many ways, sadder. If the &lt;em&gt;Iliad&lt;/em&gt; concerns what it means to die well, then the &lt;em&gt;Odyssey&lt;/em&gt; is concerned with how one might live afterward.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Tell me, Muse, of the man of many turns, who wandered far after he had sacked the sacred city of Troy.”&lt;/em&gt; Odysseus is not praised for his strength, but for his &lt;em&gt;polytropos&lt;/em&gt;—his turning mind, his adaptability, his duplicity. He is a man perpetually becoming, never quite at rest. His journey home becomes a labyrinth not of distance but of identity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
