<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Liberty on Robert Marshall</title>
    <link>https://robertmarshall.xyz/tags/liberty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Liberty on Robert Marshall</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://robertmarshall.xyz/tags/liberty/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Machinery of Men</title>
      <link>https://robertmarshall.xyz/writings/machinery-of-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://robertmarshall.xyz/writings/machinery-of-men/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Machinery of Men&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most people, if they have heard of Adam Smith at all, know him as the man who spoke of an &amp;ldquo;invisible hand.&amp;rdquo; That phrase has taken on a life of its own—half cliché, half ideology—uttered by those who have never opened &lt;em&gt;The Wealth of Nations&lt;/em&gt; and perhaps never will. I approached it out of a sense of obligation, as one might visit a grave: not expecting conversation, only reflection. But I found something else entirely. This was no dry treatise. It was a work of political philosophy clothed in the language of trade and tariffs, a forensic examination of human nature conducted through the medium of exchange.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionary’s Reply</title>
      <link>https://robertmarshall.xyz/writings/revolutionarys-reply/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://robertmarshall.xyz/writings/revolutionarys-reply/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revolutionary’s Reply&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I first read &lt;em&gt;Rights of Man&lt;/em&gt; with a sense of cautious admiration. After all, Thomas Paine had already startled me with &lt;em&gt;Common Sense&lt;/em&gt;—a pamphlet as incendiary as it was persuasive. But &lt;em&gt;Rights of Man&lt;/em&gt; was different. It bore the confidence of a man who had not only seen a revolution succeed but now sought to defend its principles against the sneers of an old order clinging to its inherited privilege. Where &lt;em&gt;Common Sense&lt;/em&gt; had spoken to the discontented colonist, &lt;em&gt;Rights of Man&lt;/em&gt; addresses a broader, more dangerous question: what gives any government the right to rule?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firebrand’s Voice</title>
      <link>https://robertmarshall.xyz/writings/firebrands-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://robertmarshall.xyz/writings/firebrands-voice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firebrand&amp;rsquo;s Voice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are some books that strike like a thunderclap when they first appear—forceful, unexpected, and impossible to ignore. Thomas Paine’s &lt;em&gt;Common Sense&lt;/em&gt; is one such work. When I first read it, I could almost hear the sound of it echoing through the narrow colonial streets of Philadelphia, rattling pews and dinner tables alike. Though clothed in the plain garments of pamphleteering, Paine’s tract is nothing less than a fierce argument for the transformation of an entire world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
